Wilfred Lim_

Mobile: +65 9725 0956 • Personal e-mail: Wilfred.Lim85@yahoo.com • Work e-mail: Wilfred LIM@scdf.gov.sg

OBJECTIVE

To introduce myself as a professional in the Singapore Civil Service and a safety and security practitioner.

BACKGROUND

Civil Servant in the Uniformed Services and Government Scholar emplaced on the Public Service Leadership Programme

PROFILE

Analytical and creative problem-solver • Command and leadership experience • Dedicated to organisational mission • Committed and accountable to team goals • Experience in managing major operations • Good tech and coding literacy (C++, PLCs, Android App dev, MatLab) • Subject matter communicator for STEM fields, safety & security, etc. • Enthusiastic and fast learner • Hands-on and always ready to tinker with any hardware • Experienced in home improvement projects

EDUCATION

National University of Singapore

Aug 2006 - Jul 2010

Bachelor of Engineering (Electrical Engineering) First Class Honours

Cumulative Average Point: 4.65 on maximum scale of 5.00

Dean's List: 2007/2008 & 2008/2009

Book Prize for Best Student in Industrial Control Systems: 2008

University of Glasgow (UK)

Jan 2009 – May 2009

Student Exchange Programme

Distinction in all Modules, equivalent to average grade of 20.57 on maximum scale of 22.00

Raffles Junior College

Jan 2002 - Dec 2003

GCE Advanced Level Certificate with excellent results

Silver Medallist for the 15th Singapore Physics Olympiad Competition 2002

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

SINGAPORE CIVIL DEFENCE FORCE

Head Operations, 3rd SCDF Division (rank of Lieutenant Colonel)

Sep 2020 – Present

 In charge of all operational matters of the Division, which comprises four fire stations in northern Singapore operating round-the-year and three National Service units holding trained reserves of rescuers and public/MRT shelter operators who can be mobilised for crises response

MINISTRY OF HOME AFFAIRS

Senior Assistant Director, Joint Operations Group (rank of Lieutenant Colonel)

Sep 2017 - Sep 2020

- Inter-agency taskforce, the Hybrid Joint Staff, to manage hybrid threats to national security
- Policy development and legislative review relating fire safety of buildings
- Regulatory policy relating to public entertainments and nightlife establishments

SINGAPORE CIVIL DEFENCE FORCE

Commander, Central Fire Station (rank of Major)

Oct 2015 - Sep 2017

- Command a staff strength of 180 to carry out emergency fire, rescue and emergency medical response to the residential downtown, and the Civic and Business districts of Singapore
- Implemented contingency responses for key national events, including F1 Singapore Grand Prix,
 National Day Parade and Shangri-La Dialogue of the International Institute for Strategic Studies
- Concurrently appointed as ad-junct lecturer at Ngee Ann Polytechnic (Dip. In Engineering Building Services and Fire Safety)

Senior Staff Officer, Operations Department (rank of Major)

May 2013 - Oct 2015

- Led a project to dynamically optimise the deployment of emergency resources, in collaboration with School of Information Systems, SMU
- Developed a masterplan to integrate smart technologies for emergency response operations, fusing the elements of command, control, communications, intelligence and surveillance
- Attended overseas security training conducted by Israeli security consultancy, ASERO Worldwide
- Part of Singapore's contingent for the humanitarian response to the 2015 Nepal earthquake (with Overseas Service Medal)

Rota Commander, Tampines Fire Station (rank of Captain)

Mar 2011 - May 2013

• Foundational posting to lead a rotational shift of 30 persons to respond to incidents